Guide to the Austin Dobson Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Austin Dobson collection
1866-1930
1880-1910
GEN MSS 930
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
9.88
(25 boxes)
The Austin Dobson collection contains letters by and to Dobson; autograph manuscripts, typescripts and proofs of works by Dobson, including poems, essays, and biographical sketches; notes and notebooks; and manuscript and printed material related to Dobson's research concerning William Hogarth. Boxes 1-4 hold letters by and to Dobson. These consist almost entirely of letters by Dobson, and recipients include: C. B. Foote; H. Buxton Freeman; Edmund Gosse; William Heinemann; E. V. Lucas; Sir Bernard Partridge; the firm of Kegan Paul; George Saintsbury; and R. F. Sketchley. Boxes 5-9 contain manuscripts of many of Dobson's poems, both in bound albums and as individual manuscripts. His occasional prose pieces are also well documented; Boxes 10-14 contain manuscripts, typescripts and proofs of a variety of essays, introductions, biographical sketches, and other prose works. Boxes 15-19 hold research materials, including notes and notebooks on various historical figures and events, and material Dobson collected while researching his biography of William Hogarth. Box 19 (Oversize) contains oversize manuscript material. Box 20 consists of individual accessions relating to Austin Dobson.
Dobson, Austin, 1840-1921
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Series I, Herman W. Liebert Collection of Austin Dobson, is the gift and bequest of Herman W. Liebert, 1963-1994. Series II, Other Austin Dobson Papers, contains discrete items acquired by the library by purchase and gift from various sources, 1960-1995. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Austin Dobson, 1840-1921
Austin Dobson, British poet and author, was born in 1840. He was educated at Beaumaris School, Anglesey; Coventry; and the Gymnase in Strasbourg. He began to work for the Board of Trade in 1856 and rose to the rank of Principal Clerk in the Harbour Department, retiring in 1901. He married Frances Mary Beardmore in 1868, and the couple had five sons and five daughters.
Beginning in 1864, Dobson began to publish verse in the magazine St. Paul's, which was edited by Anthony Trollope. His first volume of poetry, Vignettes in Rhyme, was published in 1873, followed by The Prodigals (1876) and the very popular Old-World Idylls (1883) and At the Sign of the Lyre (1885). Dobson was one of the leaders in the movement to adapt French metrical forms to English, and his poems include rondeaus, rondels, villanelles, and triolets. He was equally well known for his poems in English eighteenth-century styles, including The Ballad of Beau Brocade and the Story of Rosina.
After 1885, Dobson's major publications were in prose, and include biographies of eighteenth-century literary and historical figures, including William Hogarth, Richard Steele, Samuel Richardson, and Fanny Burney, as well as critical and occasional essays on a variety of topics, often related to the eighteenth century as well. He died at home at Ealing, London on September 2, 1921, survived by his wife and all of their children.
Scope and Contents
The Austin Dobson Collection contains letters by and to Dobson; autograph manuscripts, typescripts and proofs of works by Dobson, including poems, essays, and biographical sketches; notes and notebooks; and manuscript and printed material related to Dobson's research concerning William Hogarth.
Arrangement
Series I. Herman W. Liebert Collection of Austin Dobson, 1866-1930. Series II. Other Austin Dobson Papers, 1875-1920.
Authors, English -- 19th century; Authors, English -- 19th century -- Archives; English prose literature -- 19th century; English literature -- 19th century; English poetry -- 19th century; Authors -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Dobson, Austin, 1840-1921; Foote, C. B.; Forman, H. Buxton (Harry Buxton), 1842-1917; Gosse, Edmund, 1849-1928; Heinemann, William, 1863-1920; Lucas, E. V. (Edward Verrall), 1868-1938; Partridge, Bernard, 1861-1945; Saintsbury, George, 1845-1933; Sketchley, Richard Forster, 1826-1911; Kegan Paul, Trench, Trubner & Co
- Herman W. Liebert Collection of Austin Dobson, 1866-1930; Series I; 7.59; (19 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged in 10 subseries: Letters by Austin Dobson; Letters to Austin Dobson and Third-Party Correspondence; Poems: Albums; Poems: Individual; Essays; Introductions, Lectures, Prefaces and Reviews; Proofs; Notebooks and Notes; William Hogarth Research Materials; and Miscellaneous Papers.
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains letters by and to Dobson; autograph manuscripts, typescripts and proofs of works by Dobson, including poems, essays, and biographical sketches; notes and notebooks; and manuscript and printed material related to Dobson's research concerning William Hogarth.
  Boxes 1-4 hold letters by and to Dobson. These consist almost entirely of letters by Dobson, and recipients include: G. H. Barnes; C. B. Foote; H. Buxton Freeman; Edmund Gosse; William Heinemann; E. V. Lucas; Sir Bernard Partridge; Kegan Paul; George Saintsbury; and R. F. Sketcheley. Boxes 5-9 contain manuscripts of many of Dobson's poems, both in bound albums and as individual manuscripts. His essays and occasional prose pieces are also well-documented; Boxes 10-14 contain manuscripts, typescripts and proofs of a variety of essays, introductions, biographical sketches, and other prose works. Boxes 15-18 hold research materials, including notes and notebooks on various historical figures and events, and material Dobson collected while researching his biography of William Hogarth. Box 19 Oversize contains Oversize manuscript material.
  - Letters by Austin Dobson
    - Autograph letters, signed, to Edwin Austin Abbey (2), 1882 February 28 - November 11 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to G. A. Aitken, 1894 January 20 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to L. C. Alexander, 1888 January 30 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to W. St. Clair Baddeley, 1883 November 1 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to James Bain, 1895 July 18 - 1916 September 26 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Messrs. Ballantyne and Co., 1913 November 25 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to G. H. Barnes (6), 1885 October 13 - 1991 July 24 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter (draft) to H. C. Beeching, 1909 January 27 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mackensie Bell, 1918 April 9 (Box 1)
      General note
      Accompanied by autograph address.
    - Autograph letter, signed, to W. C. Bennett, 1877 April 14 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Benson, 1903 November 12 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Messrs. Bentley & Son, 1896 April 9 (Box 1)
      Accompanied by transcript.
    - Autograph letter, signed, to F. Bickley, 1912 January 18 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Boucicault, 1901 July 5 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to G. H. Boughton, undated (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Brown, 1902 January 29 (Box 1)
      Possibly re the poem to Kate Greenaway, "K.G."
    - Autograph letter signed to A. H. Bullen, 1891 October 29 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Charley Burney, 1904 June 1 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to W. Carey (2), 1891 April 25 - 1894 August 8 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Colonel Chester, 1880 March 9 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to R. and R. Clark, 1890 October 6 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter (draft) to Sir John Colburn, 1918 August 23 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to the Committee for the Authors Club, 1915 April 13 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Cotton, 1892 November 22 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter to [Joseph Cundall], 1879 January 25 (Box 1)
      In reply to a letter from Joseph Cundall 1879 January 22
    - Autograph letter, signed, to the Editor of the Daily Chronicle, 1916 May 16 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to F. S. Dickson, 1907 October 30 (Box 1)
      American Fielding scholar.
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Cyril Dobson, 1929 December 8 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Fanshawe, 1893 September 20 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Herbert W. Flewker, 1917 October 12 (Box 1)
      Accompanied by autograph address
    - Autograph letters, signed, to C. B. Foote (2), 1895 December 8 - 1999 January 7 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter to J. W. Ford, undated (Box 1)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to H. Buxton Forman (4), 1877 March 8 - 1909 January 11 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter to D.W. Freshfield, 1906 May 3 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter (draft) to Miss Furman, 1915 June 3 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letters (drafts) to Miss Godden, 1907 July 22 - 1909 November 16 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Sir I. Gollancz, 1917 March 20 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to Edmund Gosse (3), 1886 October 21 - 1907 April 5 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to F. Grant (3), 1883 November 18 - 1887 January 2 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to William Heinemann (8), 1992 January 1 - 1907 August 27 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, (draft) to Maurice Hewlett, 1917 September 28 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Holt, 1885 May 2 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Hutt, 1904 January 13 - 1907 July 30 (Box 1)
      Hutt of Macmillan's, re: Evelyn's diary
    - Autograph letter, signed, to L. Hutton, 1886 January 14 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to Alex H. Japp (3), 1874 November 5 - 1877 November 12 (Box 1)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to R. U. Johnson (6), 1901 August 5 - 1913 April 23 (Box 1)
      Includes 1911 March 15 letter re: Threescore and Ten.
      1913 April 23 letter re: For a closing page.
    - Autograph letter to Miss Jones, 1882 July 13 (Box 1)
    - Letter (transcript) to Kernahan, 1892 February 11 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to F. G. Kitton, 1901 August 23 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to John Lane, 1890 September 30 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Lang, 1914 March 13 (Box 2)
      Accompanied by typescript poem signed For a Blank Page, autograph address
    - Autograph letter, signed, to F. Locker-Lampson, 1874 May 26 - November 25 1886 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to E. V. Lucas (6), 1914 July 8 - 1919 April 30 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to H. W. Mabie (2), 1890 July 1 - 1892 January 8 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Macbeth, undated (Box 2)
      With autograph manuscript poem The Elixir of Life.
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Justin H. McCarthy, 1893 January 11 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to F. Macmillan, 1892 March 18 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to Sir T. Martin (2), 1888 October 25 - 1891 March 4 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Brander [Matthews], [Monday, n.y.] (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to the Editor of Mayfair, [late 1870's] (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter (draft) to Dr. Norman Moore, undated (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to John Morley, 1882 December 19 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to L. C. M. [L. C. Moulton?] (2), 1886 December 7 (Box 2)
      1886 December 7.
      Re: A Song to the Lute in Complete Poetical Works, 1887
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Dorothy Nevill, 1906 November 17 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to H. Newbolt, 1903 October 3 (Box 2)
      With autograph manuscript poem, signed, Under Which King?
    - Autograph letter, signed, (autograph quotation), to H. Norris, 1904 January 5 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to the Reverend John Oliver (3), 1908 December 20 - 1916 July 7 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter (draft) to Mr. Parkinson, 1894 June 12 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to Sir Bernard Partridge (3), 1894 May 23 - 1894 January 1 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, (2 signed), to Kegan Paul (3), 1878 February 26 - 1916 October 9 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to [James Payen-Payne], 1917 August 31 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Victor F. Piarr, 1898 March 5 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to [C. S. Pratt], 1886 May 27 (Box 2)
      Pratt, editor of Wide awake
    - Autograph letters, signed, to Colonel W. F. Prideaux (2), 1912 November 19 - 1914 October 28 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Redway, 1893 May 2 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to R. Wilkins Rees (2), 1904 October 12 - 1907 March 4 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to W. H. Rideing (2), 1904 August 3 - 1905 July 22 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Rines, 1906 August 17 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to George Saintsbury (2), 1911 June 20 - 1916 April 10 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter signed to William Bell Scott, 1876 February 6 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to William Kean Seymour, 1908 May 26 - 1918 October 14 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to R. F. Sketchley (11), 1879 July 30 - 1893 October 23 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to Reginald Smith (2), 1907 November 7- 8 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to E. C. Stedman, 1884 January 31 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Stephens, 1885 March 27 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Stoddard, 1882 June 10 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to A. Strahan (2), 1872 December 14- 19 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to William Strang, 1894 July 3 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Miss Thompson, 1903 April 23 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to D. Croal Thomson, 1902 November 23 (Box 2)
    - Autograph postcard, signed, to T. Thorp, [1906 July 21] (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to E. Turner (3), 1899 November 8 - 1918 October 14 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Watt, 1874 April 24 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Welch, 1884 December 1 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to H. B. Wheatley, 1905 January 20 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letters, signed, to Gleeson White (2), 1887 September 21 - 1894 January 19 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Williamson, 1902 May 14 (Box 2)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Woodruff, 1908 October 28 (Box 2)
    - Letter, signed, to [Thomas Wright], 1900 April 6 (Box 2)
    - Letters to unidentified correspondents, undated (Box 3)
    - Letters to unidentified correspondents, 1876-1882 (Box 3)
    - Letters to an unidentified recipient, 1883 September 28 (Box 3)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to unidentified, 1886 August 31 (Box 3)
    - Letters to unidentified correspondents, 1883-1887 (Box 3)
    - Letters to unidentified correspondents, 1888-1895 (Box 3)
    - Letters to unidentified correspondents, 1896-1905 (Box 3)
    - Letters to unidentified correspondents, 1906-1910 (Box 3)
    - Letters to unidentified correspondents, 1911-1920 (Box 3)
    - Autograph notes, signed, to "Dear madam", 1907 July 12 - 1909 June 26 (Box 3)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to "My dear Sir", 1889 September 11 (Box 3)
  - Letters to Austin Dobson and Third-Party Correspondence
    - Bell, Mackenzie: autograph letter to Austin Dobson, [1910 April 15] (Box 3)
    - Bunner, Henry C.: autograph letter to Austin Dobson, undated (Box 3)
    - Buxton-Forman, H.: autograph letter, signed, to Austin Dobson, 1900 May 6 (Box 3)
    - Greenaway, Kate: autograph letter, signed, to Austin Dobson, 1882 July 15 (Box 3)
    - Higgs, A.: 2 Autograph letters, signed, to Austin Dobson, 1908 January 18-27 (Box 3)
    - Martyr, R.E.: autograph note to Austin Dobson, 1894 May 31 (Box 3)
      Re: Goldsmith's Memoirs of a Protestant, 1895, edited by Austin Dobson.
    - Tennyson, Alfred: autograph note, signed, to Austin Dobson, no year January 6 (Box 3)
  - Poems: Albums
    - MSS Ballads Album, 1897 June 22 - 1906 October 27 (Box 4)
      Containing:
      (1) A familiar epistle to... Mr. William Hogarth. Printed. 2 pages.
      (2) A ballad of the Queen's Majesty June 22, 1897. Printed, signed by author. 2 pages.
      (3) A ballad of jubilee: autograph manuscript. 2 pages.
      (4) An epistle o the editor ("Books," 27 October 1906). Printed, signed by author. 4 pages.
      (5) A Letter to the Editor: autograph manuscript, signed. 3 pages.
    - MSS Poems Album., 1877 November 19 - 1908 June 17 (Box 4)
      (1) The ballad of imitation, autograph manuscript, signed. 2 pages.
      (2) A Whitshall Eclogue: autograph manuscript, signed. 1 page.
      (3) Batemanaetas. Pelhameius. Corvus Criticus. autograph manuscript. 1 page.
      (4) A Miltonic Cento: autograph manuscript, signed. 2 pages.
      (5) For a Picture: autograph manuscript, signed. 1 page.
      (6) An epistle to a friend: autograph manuscript, signed. 2 pages.
    - MSS Poems Album., 1876 November 21 - 1911 July 21 (Box 4)
      (1) To Hugh Thomson: autograph manuscript, signed. 1 page.
      (2) To Joseph Boulmier: autograph manuscript, 1 page.
      (3) The Passionate Printer to his Love: autograph manuscript, signed. 1 page.
      (4) To Time, the Tyrant: autograph manuscript, signed. 1 page.
      (5) With pipe and flute the mistic Pan: autograph manuscript, signed. 1 page.
      (6) To the stylis: autograph manuscript, signed. 1 page.
      (7) To the Greek girl: autograph manuscript, signed. 3 pages.
      (8) When Churchill wrote...: autograph manuscript, signed. 1 page.
      (9) Untitled poem: 4 lines, autograph manuscript, signed. 1 page.
      (10) All the Bards that write with ease: autograph manuscript, signed. 1 page.
      (11) Was he a poet?: autograph manuscript. 1 page.
    - MSS Poems Album., 1876 December 29 - 1910 January 18 (Box 4)
      (1) The Virgin with the Bells: autograph manuscript, signed.
      (2) Charles d'Orleans: autograph manuscript.
      With: manuscript poem On 'The Irritable Race' adapted from a French Bon-Mot by an unidentified author and 2 printed broadsides regarding Austin Dobson's 70th birthday.
    - MSS Poems, 1876-1905 (Box 4)
      (1) The Simple Life: autograph manuscript, signed. 2 pages.
      (2) On Pepys's Journal: autograph manuscript, signed. 1 page.
      (3) A Ballad of Names: autograph manuscript, signed. 1 page.
      (4) June (Pantoum): autograph manuscript, signed. 3 pages.
      (5) The Weathercock: autograph manuscript signed. 2 pages.
      With typescripts.
    - Notebook of early poems dated 1866. (Box 4)
      With an introductory note by Cyril Dobson.
    - Poems: autograph manuscripts of 60 poems with 38 corrected/uncorrected proofs., 1870-1896 (Box 5)
      Removed from 2 red morocco albums.
      Includes:
      (1) A sermon in stone. 1879.
      (2) The Masque of the months. 1877.
      (3) Ars Victoris. 1877.
      (4) Loves quest. 1873.
      (5) The Paradox of time. 1875.
      (6) Before Sedan. 1870.
      (7) To "Lydia Languish." 1872.
      (8) The Love letter. 1872.
      (9) Pot pourri. 1873.
      (10) Good night Babette. 1876.
      (11) A Madrigal (Before me careless lying). 1880.
      (12) An April Pastoral. 1881.
      (13) Premier's Amour. 1873.
      (14) A Dialogue from Plato. 1872.
      (15) Une Marquise. 1868.
      (16) Little Blue Ribbons. 1876.
      (17) A Fable in the Manner of Dr. Swift. 1880.
      (18) Don Quixote. 1882.
      (19) An Eastern Apologue. 1881.
      (20) To one who bids me sing. 1895.
      (21) Vilas Hainulco. 1877.
      (22) To Daffodills. 1885.
      (23) When Finis comes. 1877.
      (24) On London Stones. 1876.
      (25) On a Nankin Plate. 1883.
      (26) Tu ne Quaesieris. 1877.
      (27) The Ballad of Prose and Rhyme. 1878.
      (28) A Ballad of Heroes. 1896.
      (29) Still this may bolster thee, o friend. 1896.
      (30) To Ether. 1878.
      Album "A" 1-10
    - Poems: autograph manuscripts of 60 poems with 38 corrected/uncorrected proofs., 1870-1896 (Box 5)
      Album "A" 11-20
    - Poems: autograph manuscripts of 60 poems with 38 corrected/uncorrected proofs., 1870-1896 (Box 5)
      Album "A" 21-30
    - Poems: autograph manuscripts of 60 poems with 38 corrected/uncorrected proofs., 1870-1896 (Box 5)
      Album "B" 1-10
    - Poems: autograph manuscripts of 60 poems with 38 corrected/uncorrected proofs., 1870-1896 (Box 5)
      Album "B" 11-20
    - Poems: autograph manuscripts of 60 poems with 38 corrected/uncorrected proofs., 1870-1896 (Box 5)
      Album "B" 21-30
  - Poems: Individual
    - After a holiday, original autograph manuscript, signed, of a poem., 1866 October (Box 6)
      Accompanied by
      (1) A portrait of Austin Dobson.
      (2) Dobson, Austin. Autograph letter, signed, to "Dear Sir." 1886 November 18, London.
    - Albi, ne doleas: autograph poem, 1887 (Box 6)
      with: Ad lynam
    - April Pastoral: autograph poem, 1881 January 24 (Box 6)
    - "Au Revoir", bound original autograph manuscript, signed., 1878 August 31 (Box 6)
    - Ballad of silence: autograph manuscript, bound, of speech containing his poem, "The Ballad of Silence.", 1901 November 15 (Box 6)
      With typescript.
    - The Ballad of the Barmecide, bound original autograph manuscript, signed., 1879 March 26 (Box 6)
    - Ballad of the beggar: autograph poem., undated (Box 6)
    - Ballad of the monk: autograph poem., 1877 September 15 (Box 6)
    - Ballad of time and tennis: autograph poem., 1877 May 3 (Box 6)
    - Bells of Yule: autograph poem., 1906 October 17 (Box 6)
    - Bookworm: autograph poem., [187?] (Box 6)
    - Carmina Votiva and other occasional verses: corrected proofs., 1902 February 10 - 25 (Box 6)
      Printed by the Ballantyne Press, Edinburgh. Stamped and dated 1902, February 10 and 25. 32 pages.
      Revises of pages [511]-526, [525-526], 529-544 for his Collected Poems, 5th edition, London, 1902.
    - Carmina Votiva: Using Verses Topical and Tributary, undated (Box 6)
      Proofs, with the author's corrections and with the poems "Verses written for the Menu of the Omar Khayyám Club..." and "To the same" in manuscript, 1901. 38 leaves.
    - [Chapter of Froisssart]: manuscript in unknown hand, undated (Box 6)
    - Collaboration: corrected typescript of poem., undated (Box 6)
    - Compromise: autograph poem., undated (Box 6)
    - Conceit: autograph poem., 1917 October 10 (Box 6)
    - Cornhill Rondeau: corrected proof of poem., 1901 June 26 (Box 6)
    - Cupid's Alley: autograph of poem., 1881 March 10 (Box 6)
    - Death of a Bucaneer: autograph poem., undated (Box 6)
    - Death of Lois: autograph poem., 1868 January 21 (Box 6)
      Published in final version as Dying of Tanneguy du Bois.
    - Dialogue... Alexander Pope: autograph poem., November 1887 (Box 6)
    - Dialogue to the memory of Mr. Pope: autograph poem., undated (Box 6)
    - Dish of Tea: autograph poem., 1874 August 29 (Box 6)
    - Distressed poet: a suggestion from Hogarth: autograph poem., undated (Box 6)
    - Duo of love: autograph of poem., 1899 (Box 6)
    - A Fable in the Manner of Mr. Gay: autograph manuscript, signed., undated (Box 6)
    - Fairy tale: autograph poem., undated (Box 6)
    - Fame is the food dead men eat: autograph poem., undated (Box 6)
    - For a closing page: autograph poem., undated (Box 7)
      See Autograph letter signed to R. U. Johnson, 1913 April 23.
    - For a copy of Theocritus: autograph poem., 1879 April 6 (Box 7)
    - For another volume of essays: autograph poem., 1897 [May?] 15 (Box 7)
    - For Sir Walter Murton: 2 autographs of poem., 1912 September 7 (Box 7)
    - From the Monks and the giants: autograph poem., undated (Box 7)
    - A Gage d'Amour: autograph poem., no year November 3 (Box 7)
    - Garden song: autograph poem., undated (Box 7)
    - Gentlemen of the Old School: autograph poem., undated (Box 7)
    - "Goodnight Babette!" gallery proof of poem., undated (Box 7)